What is a jerk minimizing trajectory?
トラジェクトリーを最小化する Jerk とは何ですか?
An interesting and useful fact to us is that it is
興味深くて役立つ事実は
relatively easy to compute a jerk optimal trajectory in one dimension.
1D で jerk の最適なトラジェクトリーを計算することは相対的に簡単だということです
In fact, consider a function s of t different from time zero to time tf.
実際に 時間 0 ～tf の t の関数 s の違いを考えてみます
and recall that jerk is a third relative of position.
また jerk が位置に 3 番目に関連していることをリコールします
So the total jerk accumulated over
このトラジェクトリーの期間中の累積した jerk の合計は この方程式で
the duration of this trajectory is given by this equation.
提供されます
And here, we want to analyze both positive and negative jerk.
また ここでは正と負の両方の jerk を分析します
Therefore, we're going to look at total square jerk.
そのため jerk の 2 乗を見ていきます
Our problem is then to find a function s of t that minimizes this integral.
問題は この積分の最小値関数 t の s を見つけることです
If we go through the math required to find the minimum,
最小値を見つけるために必要な計算をしていくと
you'll find that all the time derivatives of s of order
S を jerk の最小値にするには0 にならないといけないのに
six and more have to be zero in order for S to be jerk minimal.
s の微分はいつも 6 以上になることがわかりました
Now, we can also use a helpful fact about functions,
関数についての役立つ事実も使用できます
which is that any function can be written like this or more compactly like this.
それは どの関数もこのように記述されるまたはこのくらいコンパクトに記述されるということです
When you take this form of s and add in
s のこの形式を使って
the information that we have about it's time derivative, you find this.
時間で微分した情報に追加すると これがわかります
All of the coefficient bigger than five or zero,
係数はすべて 5 か 0 より大きいです
which means that all minimum jerk trajectories
これは すべての最小限の jerk トラジェクトリーはこのように
can be represented as a fifth order polynomial like this.
5 個の多項式で表されることを意味します
You can see this equation has six coefficients and six coefficients means
この方程式には6つの係数がありますこの6つの係数は6つの調整可能なパラメータを意味し、
six tuneable parameters that we can choose
1次元のトラジェクトリーの形状を定義することができます
from in order to define the shape of a 1D trajectory.
1D で jerk の最適なトラジェクトリーを計算することは相対的に簡単だということです
And in practice, we use them to specify the boundary conditions of our trajectory.
実際には トラジェクトリーの境界条件を指定するために使用します
The things we'd like to constrain are the initial position, velocity,
制約したいことは 初期位置の速度と加速度
and acceleration as well as the final position, velocity and acceleration.
および最終位置の速度と加速度です
Now, this is just the 1D representing the longitude of displacement.
これは変位の縦方向の位置を表す1Dです
But, the same for the lateral displacement applies.
でも 横方向の移動と同じものが適用されます
This gives us 12 variables to pick in order to fully
s と d で自動車の動きを定義します
define the motion of our vehicle in S&amp;D over time.
動きを定義するために選択する 12 変数を提供します
The initial state of our vehicle give us
自動車の初期ステートは
the longitudinal and lateral boundary conditions t equals zero,
境界条件 t = 0 の緯度と経度を提供します
and we get to pick the end boundary condition.
また終了境界条件を選ぶことができます
I'm going to show you plots of what lateral trajectories look like for a simple case,
ここからここまで車が動くというシンプルな場合での
where a car moves from here to here and make
横方向のトラジェクトリーがどのようなものかの構想をお見せします
the simplifying assumption that
また 初期と最後の横方向の速度と加速度が 0 という
the initial and final lateral velocities and accelerations are zero.
簡略化した仮定を作成します
Which is reasonable for lane change.
それは車線変更には合理的です
Then, all boundary conditions look like this.
そして すべての境界条件はこのようになります
And the only nonzero quantity of this 1D problem is the final lateral displacement.
この 1D 問題の 0 でない量だけが最終の横方向移動です
Let's look at what some of these trajectories look like.
これらのトラジェクトリーがどのように見えるのかを確認してみましょう
Keep in mind, this is a one dimensional motion.
これは 1D の動きということを覚えておいてください
The X axis here is time and
ここの X 軸は時間で
the Y axis is lateral position of the vehicle as it makes its lane change.
その車線変更をするので Y 軸は自動車の横方向の位置です
The F and T are the final lateral displacements and the duration of our trajectory.
F と T は最終の横方向移動とトラジェクトリーの時間です
You can see at equal zero,
= 0 で
the position is zero.
位置が 0 であることがわかります
The slope is zero so velocity is now and so is acceleration.
スロープは 0 です そのため 速度も今は 0 で 加速度も同じく 0 です
Likewise, for the final position that equals 10.
同じように 最終位置の場合は = 10 です
And this curves looks pretty smooth.
この曲線はとてもなめらかです
But let's also look at velocity over time and acceleration over time.
でも 速度と加速度を見ていきましょう
Although not all of these curves might be meaningful to you,
これらの曲線のすべてが意味あるものではないかもしれませんが
let's think back about what just happened here.
ここで発生したことを振り返ってみましょう
We've specified a position we wanted to reach and a time we wanted to
いくつかの質問で たどり着きたい位置とそれにかける時間を指定しました
reach it at in some equations and we end up with a nice looking trajectory.
そして とてもきれいなトラジェクトリーを取得できました
It's very nice indeed because a lot of drivers would not attain
それはとても素晴らしいです その理由は
that level of comfort if we were to ask them to reproduce it.
再現するようにドライバーにたずねても 多くのドライバーは快適レベルに達しないからです
Now, let's see what happens if I try to reach the destinations more
では T を下げてもっと速く目的地にたどり着こうとしたら
quickly by turning down T. Sure enough,
何が起こるか見てみましょう
we can still find the trajectory over time,
もちろん 徐々にトラジェクトリーを見つけることもできますが
but it's much more jerky.
それはもっと大変です
It is important to realize that although the trajectory that we generate
このメソッドまたは境界条件の与えられたセットの jerk 最適化を使用して
using this method or jerk optimal for a given set of boundary conditions,
トラジェクトリーを生成しましたが
they still depend heavily on these conditions.
これらの条件にとても依存しているということを認識することは重要です
Therefore, it would be important in the future to wisely pick these end conditions.
そのため 今後幅広くこれらの終了条件を選ぶことが重要になるでしょう
Now, I want to show you how I computed what
では これらの境界条件を満たすために
the six coefficient had to be in order to satisfy these boundary conditions.
この 6 つの係数がどうなるかをどのように計算したかをお見せします